Oh, my.
Where was this happening?
Robert E. Lee Park. I was
on the roof across the way.
What if some small child
or anybody walked by?
I know.
That one's good. You
can see his face so clearly.
Well, I never.
No?
I mean... Ben?
Out here.
Hi. Cliff here?
Hi, Billy. Cliff's
out for a run.
That's all he ever does
anymore is exercise.
Friends of yours?
Surveillance photos.
Ben, you shouldn't be
looking at pictures like that.
A man your age.
What about my age?
Well, I heard a man your
age look at something like that,
he's liable to keel
right over, heart attack.
What about your age?
Oh, well, I...
I look at them
scientifically. Ha, ha.
- They don't affect me.
- Ah.
- What'd you come over here for?
- Borrow your car.
Mine's in the shop.
I gotta get down to my
stockbroker's. It's an emergency.
Every stock I bought has split.
Broker's never
seen anything like it.
I keep having to go
down there and sign stuff
so he can keep
rolling over my money.
Yeah, okay.
- Got gas in it?
- Eh.
- Oh, hey, Pop.
- Good Lord.
You look like you
fell in a water hole.
- Hi, Cliff.
- Hi, everyone.
Hey, I have an
announcement to make.
You may have noticed that
I've been doing a lot of running
and biking and swimming.
- Oh, thank you.
- No, you're dripping on the floor.
Oh, I'm sorry. Uh...
Anyway, there's a triathlon
up in Wilmington next week,
and I've entered it.
Good for you, Cliff.
Yeah. Anyway, it's something
I wanted to do,
and I'm gonna do it.
And it would mean an awful
lot to me to have you all there,
to, you know, cheer me on.
Well, are you sure, Cliff?
I mean, a lot of strong
people enter those things.
Yeah.
Are you saying
my boy can't do it?
- Well, I didn't say that, I...
- But you're thinking it, aren't you?
Well...
- I'll be there, son.
- Oh, yeah.
And if you want Ben and
Jerri, they'll be there too.
Okay, thanks, Pop.
I'll rent us a nice big
house on the beach
with daily maid service
and our own cook, huh?
I'm in.
I'll even spring for
the plane tickets.
I'll rent the car
and buy all the groceries.
You won't have
to pay for a thing.
Okay.
Two, three, four.
Again, one, two, three, four.
Good.
So you have that wonderful gym
and playroom downstairs.
And adjacent to the family
room, we have the kitchen.
With all the amenities
you could possibly ask for
and a view to die for.
- We'll take it.
- Good.
Well, Billy, you didn't
find out how much.
Oh, yeah.
What kind of rent
are we talking about?
Four thousand, five
hundred dollars a month.
Which includes all utilities,
plus the usual $500
damage deposit.
We'll take it.
But we're only gonna
be here a week.
What kind of rent are we
talking about by the week?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'd still have to charge
you for the full month.
That's all right, we'll take it.
Billy...
Ben, I like this place.
It gives me good vibes.
Vibes?
Yeah, you know, vibes.
Now, if you wanna
know the truth,
so does she.
- Miss Montrose.
- Yes?
- Personal check okay?
- Great.
I think you've made
a very wise choice.
- Oh, thank you. Ha-ha-ha.
- Please.
Oh, isn't that cute.
Look, there's a
little peach tree on it.
I'm kind of
partial to plant life.
I used to be a farmer.
Really?
- You wanna go for a walk?
- Yeah, they say five's a crowd.
Cliff, you wanna join us?
No, no. I'm gonna unpack the bike,
go for a ride. I'll see you all later.
Have a good time.
- Come on, I'll race you.
- Yeah.
- You want some?
- Huh?
No.
Reduces your risk of
premature aging and skin cancer.
Yeah. Five years from now,
they're gonna come out with a study
- says that stuff gives you cancer.
- Ha-ha-ha.
What do you think?
To the pier and back?
Let's hit it.
- It's nice.
- Yeah.
I can't remember when I've
taken a trip that I had nothing to do.
- Ha. It's good to have nothing to do.
- Yeah.
And it's great that Cliff
is doing this triathlon.
I hope it works out.
The boy's been known
to sprain his ankle
- running for the phone.
- Ha-ha-ha.
He's gonna do it.
It'll be good for him.
Good for his body
and good for his mind.
You ever done stuff like that?
- Damn.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Good for the body, good for the mind.
- Yeah.
Well, I'll be.
What?
- Well, I'll be.
- What?
Ed?
Hello, Ben.
What you doing?
Go down to the water.
I'll meet you there.
You stay here.
Who's that?
Ed Wingate, an FBI
agent I represented once.
Who's the babe?
My investigator.
What's going on?
You two.
Stop the roughhousing
before somebody gets hurt.
Are you a lifeguard?
I'm undercover.
Your Christmas
card said you retired.
Just a little
unfinished business.
It was nice seeing you, Ben.
But in the future,
if you see me,
pretend you didn't.
Oh, it's a hot one, huh?
- Hey, Cliff.
- Ooh.
- What happened?
- Oh, uh, I had a little fall. No big deal.
Ooh, that's nasty.
Where did you do it?
Uh, out on a steep grade.
Here you go, son.
This'll fix you up like new.
Lucky you were in the
driveway when you fell.
Here, let me help you with that.
So, uh, how was your walk?
- Guess who's here.
- Who?
- Ed Wingate.
- No.
- What's he doing here?
- He's undercover.
- Did he have on the sunglasses?
- That's how I recognized him.
What is the deal with
this Ed Wingate guy?
Oh, well, he's, um...
- He's indescribable.
- Yeah. Ha-ha-ha.
Ha-ha-ha. Ow!
- Oh, sorry.
- Hey, shh. Hold it down.
Hello, Anita?
It's Billy.
Billy.
Billy Lewis.
The guy you just
rented the house to.
Yeah.
Well, actually,
there is a problem.
Uh, the toilets won't flush.
Yeah, you hit the little handle
and it just sort of swirls around,
doesn't go anywhere.
Oh, you don't have to do that.
Well, maybe you're
right. It's a good idea.
Yeah. I'll see you then.
Bye.
She's, uh, sending a plumber over,
and then she's coming out herself.
There's nothing wrong
with the toilets, Pop.
I know.
Billy, she's not gonna wanna
see you when she finds out
she's come all the way
out here for nothing.
Ben, when she gets out here,
I'm gonna tell her I fixed
the toilets all by myself.
Well, Billy...
Eh. I've still got it,
don't I? Ha-ha-ha.
Are you okay?
You okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I think so.
I'm so sorry. It's all my fault,
drifting out in front of you like that.
- I am so sorry.
- Oh, no, no, no.
It wasn't entirely your fault.
After all, I was moving
at a rate of speed
that could only
be described as...
Well, pushing open the envelope.
- You're here for the triathlon?
- Well, yes, I am.
Oh, no, now I've
ruined it for you.
Oh, no, no. No, this
is just a little road rash.
Look, my car's right over
there. Maybe I should take you
- to an emergency room.
- No, no, no, I'm fine.
Let me at least give you
a lift back to your hotel.
You know, you really
should take a hot bath.
The best way to get the grit out
of those scrapes is to soak it out.
You sound like a nurse.
Actually, I'm a
stockbroker. Kathy Bridges.
Oh. Ted Winston,
molecular biochemist.
- Aah, ow.
- Oh!
Oh, that's all right.
Here. You know how
to tie a line off to a cleat?
- Of course I do.
- Good. Glad somebody does.
How was the trip?
Please, boats make
passages, not trips.
Jeez, Thomas, what
kind of barbarian are you?
- So how was the passage?
- Lousy.
I'm driving home, I can
tell you that right now.
Spent the whole time
feeding the fishes.
Gotta do something about
that stomach, Ronerino.
Yeah, look who's
talking. Heads up there.
No, thanks. I brought my own.
His body's a temple,
you remember?
Just stay downwind of
me with that thing, will you?
Well, hail, hail, the gang's all
here. So, what's the word, Thomas?
How's everything look
to you two triathlon-ites?
Well, you'd be amazed how
informative people can be
when they think
you're just a tourist.
Gentlemen, we're
gonna be very rich.
One small problem
notwithstanding.
- Well, what's the problem?
- Ed Wingate's here.
You're kidding me, right?
- I thought you said he retired.
- There's no need to panic.
It might just be a coincidence.
In any case, I'm on
top of it so don't worry.
- How's that feel?
- Oh, it's great. Thanks.
- You were right.
- Just sit back
and let that heat penetrate
those tight muscles of yours.
There's this great Chinese
restaurant takeout down the street.
What do you like? I'll
go get you something.
Oh, no, no. You
don't have to do that.
I know, but I want to.
It'd make me feel
better. Please?
They have great
chicken chow mein.
All right, but tell
them to hold the MSG.
- Well, how about some ribs?
- No, I prefer carbohydrates.
Sixty-five percent of
the calories in pork ribs
are derived from fat.
I like to maintain a body
count level at about 11 percent,
just to hedge against
disease, you know?
No problem.
Okay. Now the only question is,
- when do we make our move?
- Soon, I hope.
Well, actually, I have a little plan
if we have to distract Ed Wingate.
Well, that's the
understatement of the year.
- Hello?
- Oh. Come on up.
Watch your step.
Not that I'm complaining,
but who the hell is she?
Kathy Bridges, Dennis Lamont.
That's Ron Jaffe.
Of course, you know Al.
Kathy's an old friend
of mine from Raleigh.
She's been researching
our little problem, Ed Wingate.
He's been taking
pictures of you and Al.
Damn. That's to prove we're
here and up to something.
What's this guy's problem? The
rest of the FBI blew us off years ago.
Yeah, I thought you
said Eddie'd retired.
Okay, hey, we can handle this.
You think he's onto you?
No, to him I'm just a nice little
local girl who can't ride a bike.
Okay, like I said,
we can handle this.
It's just gonna take a
little more time, that's all.
Woo-hoo! Billy!
So you fixed them all yourself?
Yeah.
What about the
plumber I sent over?
Didn't have to do a thing.
Oh, don't worry, I paid
him for coming out.
Well, I guess that takes
care of everything then.
Well, actually, uh...
I was wondering, I mean,
as long as you're here,
later maybe we...
Ah, Mr. Matlock. Hello.
Oh, hello again, Mrs. Montrose.
Or is it Miss Montrose?
It's Anita. I'm widowed.
So to tell you the truth, I'm not
sure what my last name is anymore.
Oh, ha-ha-ha.
- How do you like the house?
- Oh, it's just, uh...
Uh, it's, uh,
perfect. Just perfect.
Excuse me, I'm... The phone.
Sure.
He's always on the phone.
Work, work, work.
That's all he ever does.
Now, me, I, uh...
Heh. I like to stop and smell
the roses every chance I get.
That and fix toilets.
- Billy? Heh.
- Yeah.
I'm just being nice,
and he thinks I'm trying
to steal his woman.
It's not good for you.
I don't care.
A person gets to
have a little fun.
- Cliff out on his bike?
- Yep.
You know, I was
wondering something.
- What?
- Well, I probably
shouldn't say anything
about it, but, you know,
Cliff hadn't had a lot
of luck with girls lately.
And Cliff, like his father, is
unusual and complicated.
I just wonder if he's doing
this triathlon for himself
or to, uh, impress you.
Oh, I don't think so.
I explained to Cliff
that I recently broke
up with somebody,
and I don't wanna get
involved with anybody yet.
- We have an understanding.
- Hm.
Maybe he doesn't
understand the understanding.
I just asked Anita to
dinner, and she accepted.
- Hey.
- Hey, have fun.
Too bad, Ben.
I guess the better man won.
Hi, Ed.
It's not me.
Okay.
How did you know it was me?
Like any mother
knows her children, Ed.
All right, follow me, but, uh,
keep reading your newspaper.
Why are you limping?
You're very observant. You
would've made a fine FBI agent.
No, I don't like
to wear dresses.
Well, cross-dressing
is almost a lost art.
I don't really enjoy it myself,
but when duty compels me,
I must admit in all modesty
that I usually achieve
spectacular results.
That's because
you've got nice legs.
Thank you.
Can I ask you
something personal?
Ask away.
What's the matter with you?
You gotta be more specific.
Well, you're retired.
You had a fine
career with the FBI.
Why are you down
here running around
after would-be, could-be,
might-be bank robbers?
You ought to be out
playing horseshoes or fishing.
I hate horseshoes.
You know what I mean.
Ben, you know who my hero
was when I was growing up?
No.
Robert Stack as Elliot
Ness in The Untouchables.
I used to say to
my mom... I'd say:
"Virginia, when I grow
up, I wanna be a G-man."
You called your mother Virginia?
That was her name.
You want some coffee?
I'm buying.
Huh.
Thanks.
Turn your back to me.
Okay, dude, I want
two coffees, black.
And a bear claw.
Hey, Ed, the bear claw.
Ed, you there?
I'm slipping, Ben.
I'm losing my edge.
Been out to pasture too long.
What are you talking about?
From now on, you
really don't know me.
That is a huge bear claw.
That'll be 2.45, sir.
Come on, get it!
Get it, get it, get it!
Okay, one more
mile. You can do it.
All right.
- You got it.
- Ready?
- What's up?
- Ed Wingate called.
He left a message asking
me to meet him for drinks.
- What do you want me to do?
- Go.
- See you later.
- All right, see you.
- Hi.
- Hello again.
I wanted to thank you again for
what you did for me yesterday.
Oh, I was happy to do it.
- I got your message.
- So I see.
- What will you have to drink?
- Whatever you're having is fine.
So how are you?
Still pretty sore?
Oh, no, no, I'm fine.
Matter of fact, I did a
little sightseeing today.
- Good for you. Where'd you go?
- Everywhere.
Everywhere you went.
- Excuse me?
- You're messing with the FBI.
FBI? What are you talking about?
Did you tell Thomas Crighton I'd been
following him, taking pictures of him?
Who?
This guy. Thomas Crighton.
I saw you talking to him
in the parking lot at
the beach this morning.
He's just somebody I met
at a bar a couple nights ago.
I barely know him. Not
that it's any of your business.
Look, I gotta tell you,
I don't like the idea of
you following me one bit.
Give it up, Kathy. I'm onto you.
The key gave you away.
- What key?
- The one to my briefcase.
I keep it in my left
pants pocket. Always.
This morning, it was in
my right pants pocket.
You put in in the wrong pants pocket
after you went through my briefcase.
- That does it. You are wacko.
- Please.
- Let go of me.
- Sit down.
What is Thomas
Crighton doing here?
I don't know.
He said he was here for
the triathlon. That hurts!
All right.
Crighton's onto
me, thanks to you.
So I want you to
tell him that this time,
I'm going to get him.
Just stay away from
me, you nutcase!
Yeah, it's Ron.
I went to the bar to keep an
eye on things like you said.
Hold on a minute.
I gotta tell you, I
think we got problems.
- Hi, Cliff.
- Hey, Ben.
What you eating?
Dinner.
That's pure starch.
These are carbohydrates.
Nobody calls this starch
anymore. I'm carbo-loading.
That's what athletes
do before a big race.
- They, you know, store up energy.
- Ah.
You remember that time
that you took that 10-mile run?
- Yeah.
- Remember what happened after?
I threw up.
But I'm only running
6 miles this time.
And swim a mile and a
half and ride a bike 25 miles.
You're gonna throw up again.
Well, so, what if I do? So what?
I'm sure other people will too.
Why do you do that to yourself?
Well, I set a goal, and
I'm gonna achieve it.
Everyone should challenge
themselves once in a while.
- It's good for the soul.
- Hi, Ed.
I wish you wouldn't...
How'd you get in here?
Apparently you've forgotten.
- I am the wind.
- You are the wind.
I know you've defended several
other cases here in Wilmington.
And as a result, you're
acquainted with the local police.
I want you to take
them this glass.
Have them lift any and all fingerprints
and run it through their computer.
And when they ask why?
Make up something.
You were with the
FBI. Have their lab do it.
Number one, in
case you've forgotten,
I wasn't exactly liked
by my colleagues.
And number two, my erstwhile
employers do tend to frown
upon unauthorized
investigations.
Well, I don't know, Ed.
It seems to me if I'm
gonna do you a favor,
the least you could
do is tell me what...
He's gone.
He's the wind.
Our Father, we thank you
for bringing us
together in this place
and for granting us the
benediction of your weather.
Bless these athletes
in their endeavor
and let them complete
their course in safety
and in the spirit of
good competition.
All of which we ask in
your holy name. Amen.
Two minutes. The race
will begin in two minutes.
All contestants should
be in the starting area.
So, Al, what do you say
we make this interesting?
Two hundred bucks
says I finish before you do.
- Two thousand bucks says I do.
- Oh.
You're on.
You shouldn't drink so much water
before you start. You might drown.
One minute. The race
will begin in one minute.
All contestants to the
starting area immediately.
- Well, that's me.
- Yeah.
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
- Thanks. Okay.
- Good luck, tiger. Go get them.
Would Ben Matlock please
report to the official's table?
Ben Matlock, to the
official's table, please.
That's you.
Yeah. Wonder what they want.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
I immediately called the
locals who questioned me
for the better part of the
night and then let me go.
They didn't arrest me until
they talked to the people
who were at the bar where
she and I had drinks yesterday.
"All four witnesses indicate
that Miss Bridges
tried to leave the table."
I reseated her.
"And that an argument between
Mr. Wingate and Miss Bridges ensued.
Three out of four recall seeing
Mr. Wingate apply physical force
to keep her at the table."
I applied an FBI-sanctioned
restraint and twisted a little.
What about the motel
maintenance man?
What about him?
"Who, while repairing the ice
machine at around 8:15 p.m.,
saw Mr. Wingate entering
room number 5 with a woman
who appeared to be
extremely intoxicated."
Obviously he saw the
real killer dump the body
and just assumed it was me.
Well, the DA thinks that
he can convince the jury
that you strangled
Kathy Bridges to death.
Surely you can convince
a jury that that is ridiculous.
Not if you don't tell me
what's going on, I can't.
Seventeen, 18,
nineteen, 20.
You're looking
good, baby! Come on!
Twenty-one minutes.
- All right.
- Looking good. Keep it up.
Twenty-four.
All right, looking
good. Keep it up.
Twenty-five, 26.
All right, showers
down there to your right.
- Go, go.
- Hey.
We're at 21:20.
- Looking good.
- Go, go, go.
All racers, watch out for bikes
in the transition area.
Remember you must have your...
- Where you been?
- Oh, I was just pacing myself.
This is gonna be so
easy, I almost feel guilty.
Yeah, the race is young, Al.
- Yeah, we'll see.
- Yeah.
Moving out in an
orderly fashion.
Well, might as well relax.
He's gonna be a while.
Yeah.
Let's go down to the dock.
Maybe we can catch him there.
Okay.
Four years ago, down in Charleston,
there was an armored car robbery.
Seven million dollars
in cash was stolen.
The FBI investigated,
as did local authorities,
but no arrests were ever made,
and the money was never recovered.
I eventually figured
out who did it.
But unfortunately, I was
never able to prove anything.
And, consequently, the
perpetrators went free,
and the case was entered
on the books as unsolved.
- You didn't like that, I guess.
- I hated it.
But there was nothing
I could do about it.
Until about a month ago.
What happened a month ago?
I learned that the man
who masterminded the heist
about four years
ago, Thomas Crighton,
was coming up here to
participate in the triathlon.
Then I found out that his partner,
Al Ducow, was in the race too.
Been following them
since the day they arrived.
Why?
Because they're
gonna pull another heist.
Only this time, I'm
gonna nail them.
Ed, you're re...
Why don't you just be retired?
Once an instrument of justice,
always an instrument of justice.
Hmm.
Well, what makes you think
there's gonna be a heist?
Three days ago,
Thomas Crighton's other two
accomplices sailed into town.
They're all here, Ben.
Now, something big
is about to go down.
Mark my words.
What's, uh, Kathy
Bridges got to do with it?
Thomas Crighton must've
suspected that I was on his tail,
and so he hired her to
find out how much I knew.
Those were her fingerprints
on the glass I gave you.
- Did you ever give those to the police?
- She's from Raleigh.
She has a rap sheet.
Nothing important.
You realize the DA's gonna
find out that I asked the police
to run a check on her, and
he's gonna wanna ask questions.
And, uh, after he figures out
that she was working
for Thomas Crighton,
he'll turn it into
some kind of motive.
Yeah.
This isn't going to be the no-brainer
it was supposed to be, is it?
No.
Cliff. We thought you'd drowned.
- How you feeling, son?
- You did it.
I feel good. I feel really good.
My legs are a little wobbly. I
haven't been on dry land for a while.
Can't even tell
if they're moving.
Are they moving?
Yeah, they're moving,
they're moving.
I've had it. You never told me it
was gonna be like this. I'm out of here.
- Where are you going?
- For a walk somewhere
- where the ground don't move.
- Yeah, well, try L.A.
I spend one more minute on
this, I'm going stark raving bonkers.
Well, you know what your problem
is, son? You don't drink enough.
Hey.
You're Ron Jaffe and
you're Dennis Lamont, right?
Well, yeah.
- What can I do for you?
- I'm Ben Matlock.
- Mind if I come aboard?
- Well, sure, sure.
Now, how do you know who we are?
I've been talking to Ed Wingate.
Ed Wingate. Huh. Ha.
- Why does that name ring a bell?
- He's an FBI agent.
He's been trying to pin that
robbery down in Charleston on you.
Oh, Ed. Yeah,
Eddie, the lunatic.
What's he to you?
Uh, he's my client.
He's been charged with
murdering Kathy Bridges,
and I'm representing him.
I understand that she used to
work for your pal, Thomas Crighton.
Well, I thought he
said he met her in a bar.
No. She worked for him.
Hi, guys.
Ed, what are you doing here?
Well, I thought I should
come say hello to the boys.
Why don't you get off my boat?
Dennis, is that any way
to treat an old friend?
I said leave.
Let's go, Ed. This is
no place for both of us.
Wait a minute.
I just wanted you to know that
I'm gonna be on you like a shirt.
One of you killed Kathy Bridges
and framed me for murder.
I said, get off my boat now!
As I was saying,
this time I'm going to get you.
Let's go.
That was smart, Ed. Real smart.
All contestants,
be careful of water
coming into the transition area.
Careful with the bikes
in the transition area.
Make sure your
numbers are on the front.
Where is he?
All the numbers on
the front of your body.
Everybody, be careful of
water in the transition area.
On your left.
On your right.
All placers, please
watch the water
in the transition area.
Billy?
Anita. Ha, ha.
Mm.
I was showing a house
a couple blocks away,
so I thought I'd just stop
by and watch for a little while
- before my next appointment.
- Yeah.
Hi, Jerri.
- Hi, Anita, how are you?
- How are you?
You're wearing the necklace
I bought you last night.
Well, I couldn't very
well wear the blender.
He bought you a blender?
Yeah, so we could make
margaritas on the beach.
- Or anywhere.
- Or anywhere, yeah. Ha, ha.
Speaking of that, I was
wondering if later maybe today...
There he is!
Oh.
Hey. Ha-ha-ha.
Yippee!
- Hi, Cliff.
- Hey.
- How are you doing?
- Doing real good.
- Oh, good.
- Feeling pretty good.
Hey, Pop.
Right here, son.
Anita's here too.
- Hi, Cliff.
- Hey, Anita.
- Will you all do me a favor?
- Sure, what?
Catch me.
- Come on.
- Here we go!
- All right.
- Hey.
- Yeah.
- All right!
Al!
Here you go, man.
You look like you
could use a drink.
Still trying to figure out
where I'm gonna
spend that extra 2 grand.
- Still got 3 miles to go, buddy-boy.
- Yeah. Catch me.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Hey, why don't you watch
- where you're going?
- I'm sorry.
- Jerk.
- Excuse me.
- Ben, where you been?
- I'll tell you later.
- Where's...? Where's Cliff?
- He's coming right now.
He's still on his feet.
He's gonna need some water.
- He looks awful.
- That's my boy.
Let's hear it for the
annual Wilmington triathlon.
Finishers are coming down.
It's a pretty close race here.
Give them a round of applause.
Who's gonna come
across the line first?
It's number 67.
All right, everybody,
let's hear it!
- Let's give a round of applause.
- We should see him soon.
Come on, let's hear it.
- You okay, Al?
- Yeah.
Feel a little lightheaded,
that's all. You go ahead.
No, no, no, we'll
cross together.
No, no, I can afford
to lose the bet, Tom.
Nobody loses today.
Come on. I'm gonna
get you in the shade.
All right.
We've got good times today.
All right, looking good.
Number 85 coming
down the home stretch.
All right, let's go! Let's go!
Let's keep it up, number 7.
There he is.
Now, that last bend. Let's
give number 7 a big hand.
Big round of applause.
He's gonna make it, folks.
He's gonna make it.
Oh, you did it, Cliff. You
actually, honestly did it.
- I knew I could. I knew I could.
- I'm proud of you, son.
You gonna throw up?
No, not right now. Although
I can't rule it out entirely.
Here, put this around you.
Cool you off.
How do you feel?
- Not very good.
- Doctor.
Somebody get a doctor over here!
- What happened?
- He just collapsed.
- I think he had a heart attack.
- Okay.
- Easy.
- Al?
- Can you hear me?
- Is he gonna be all right?
I don't know, sir.
- He's not breathing.
- Come on, Al.
So Ed Wingate thinks
this Crighton guy killed her?
Well, one of the three of them.
And they framed Ed to
get him out of the way.
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
He thinks they're gonna
pull off another heist.
He still in jail?
No, I bailed him out.
He promised me he'd stay
home and behave himself,
and the next thing I know,
he's down at the marina
and in a fight with
Dennis Lamont.
Well, he doesn't really
seem like the type
who can stay out of trouble.
Come on, sit down.
No. No, I can't.
My heinie's a little sore
from all the bike riding.
Cliff, why don't
you take a walk?
It'll help keep your
legs from stiffening up.
I can't. My thighs are all
chafed from all the running I did.
- Well, lie down somewhere.
- I can't.
I sleep on my right side,
and that's the side I fell on.
Oh, my gosh.
She can't be here already.
- Who?
- Anita.
I asked her to come over.
She's bringing the blender.
She's bringing what?
Margaritas.
Well, if you're just gonna stand
there, at least put on a clean shirt.
Jerri, get the door, will you?
I gotta straighten up here.
Okay.
Be right there, Anita.
Hello, darling. And
how are we all today?
Whatever you got, I don't
want any. Relax, Billy, it isn't her!
Ed Wingate, FBI.
Just smile along and let me in.
Gentlemen, I believe
you know this person.
Hello, Ed.
What are you doing?
You gave me your word.
Surely you didn't believe me.
- Why are you dressed like that?
- They may be watching.
Who might be watching?
You don't need to know that yet.
Al Ducow is dead.
Yeah, they were giving
him CPR when we left.
Couldn't revive him.
Apparent heart attack.
See? People die from triathlons.
And that man wasn't
much older than you.
Did you throw up yet?
No, I feel a lot better.
Don't talk to me like that.
I believe that Thomas Crighton
is responsible for his death.
- Why do you say that?
- Al Ducow was 34,
didn't drink, didn't smoke,
was genetically sound,
and had a cholesterol
level of 128.
Not exactly heart
attack material.
It doesn't make sense.
If Thomas Crighton was
gonna pull off a robbery,
why would he kill somebody
that was gonna help him?
I haven't figured
that out yet, Ben.
But, uh, I do know this.
On Friday morning, $6
million will be delivered
to the Security Central Bank,
and they are going to hit it.
Mark my words.
Did you check out Kathy
Bridges' hotel room yet?
- I'm gonna do it right now.
- Good.
I'll be in touch.
You better see me to the door.
Your slip's showing.
Thanks.
Strange.
Got nice legs, though.
How long's the hotel
gonna keep her clothes?
I don't know. They can't
find anybody to send it to.
If Kathy had any friends or
relatives, nobody wants to step up.
This Ed Wingate, was
he really an FBI agent?
One of the best.
Is he married?
Well, being an instrument of
justice has always kept him too busy.
You interested?
Wears too much mascara.
What's this?
"Redbird 208."
I don't get it. How could
Al have a heart attack?
He was the healthiest
person I've ever seen.
Yeah, well, these things happen.
I mean, remember Jim Fixx?
I can't believe AI's gone.
And so is Kathy Bridges.
Yeah, well, police
picked up Agent Wingate.
Somehow I thought maybe one of
you two might know something about it.
Hey, you're the one
she was buddies with.
That's right, we were
friends. Why would I kill her?
Well, well, Mr. Matlock.
Hi.
I'm Ben Matlock.
You're Thomas Crighton.
Nice to meet you.
I understand you're kind of
the ringleader around here.
Excuse me?
Yeah, Mr. Matlock is,
uh, Ed Wingate's attorney.
You remember Eddie Wingate,
don't you? That lunatic from the FBI?
Well, I wouldn't
call him a lunatic.
After all, he was smart
enough to figure out
it was you that beat the
alarm on that armored car heist
in Charleston four years ago.
And Mr. Jaffe drove
the getaway vehicle,
and Al Ducow jumped
down into the garage
where the car was parked.
Terrible thing that
happened to Mr. Ducow.
Yes, it is.
Yeah, Mr. Matlock came by earlier.
He was asking about, uh, Kathy Bridges.
Of course I told him
you met her at that bar.
That's right. I met her
a couple of nights ago.
I barely knew her.
So before a couple of days
ago, you never spoke to her?
- That's right.
- Well, that's odd. I, uh...
I found this piece
of paper in her room.
That's your motel and
room number, isn't it?
Yeah, well, I may be
staying at the Redbird,
but that's not my room number.
But it was. You moved
a week ago, remember?
You must have known
her longer than two days.
You just lied to me. Why?
I didn't lie. I just forgot.
I mean, I guess I did
know her a week ago.
You know, Mr. Matlock, uh,
instead of letting your client suck you
into the same old wild goose chase
he's been on for the last four years,
maybe you might better
go down and talk to the FBI.
They'll be able to fill in you
on old Agent Eddie Wingate
and that hyperactive
imagination of his.
And don't be surprised if
they use the word lunatic too.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Ed's full of surprises.
Well, uh, nice to meet
you, and I'll see you around.
It's so sweet of you
to bring me here.
- Been here before?
- Couple of times.
It's expensive.
The food is fabulous.
Oh, well, order whatever you
want. Don't worry about the cost.
What's money for anyway?
You'd think at
these prices, though,
they could afford a few
decent light bulbs in here.
That's atmosphere, Billy.
Oh.
It is so quiet and
beautiful here.
It reminds me of Lake Como.
Is that around here?
Hmm?
No.
Lake Como's in Italy.
It's one of my favorite
places in the entire world.
I love the way you talk.
You know what you are?
- No.
- You are the cat's meow.
Oh, heh.
Wow.
When it's peach
pickin' time in Georgia
Apple pickin' time in Tennessee
Ben, must you do that in here?
Cotton pickin'
time in Mississippi
- Everybody picks on me
- When it's roundup time in Texas
- The boys all make whoopee
- Way down south in Alabama
- It's gal pickin' time for me
I hope the preacher
knows His business
- I know he can't fool me
When it's peach
pickin' time In Georgia
- It's gal pickin' time for me
Jerri? Jerri?
Jerri?
What?
Haven't I suffered enough?
Even that caterwauling of yours
sounds good to me tonight, Ben.
That's how good a mood I'm in.
Where'd you go?
The Marina Club.
Spent $235.
On dinner?
Had lobster and champagne.
She likes this real
expensive Don...
Somebody stuff.
- So you had fun?
- Fun? Ah.
Soft organ music, a
wandering accordion,
low mood lights,
and Anita.
I gotta get to bed
and dream. Ha-ha-ha.
I'm chartering a boat
tomorrow to take her fishing.
And soon maybe I'll be
taking her to Lake Como.
That's nice. Is
that around here?
It's in Italy, Cliff. Italy.
Near Paris.
Nita Juanita
Did he just say he's
taking her to Europe?
Yes, he's taking her...
Don't. Stop laughing.
It's not funny. Now
I'm really worried.
- About what?
He's only known her a week.
He's flashing his money around.
Champagne dinners,
trips to Europe.
I'll tell you, this is the kind of thing
that could leave him high and dry.
And alone.
Hmm. It's happened before.
Cliff, your dad's old enough
to take care of himself.
Oh, Pop.
When you were poor,
life was so much simpler.
Maybe it will be again.
I gotta talk to him.
- Oh.
- Thanks.
Oh, you're looking for jacks.
I needed that.
Okay, you gotta
help me with this.
Cliff, I don't know
how I feel about this.
Gin.
Ben, you brought it
up in the first place.
I didn't bring it up.
You brought it up.
Maybe she likes Billy
because he's Billy.
Might be far-fetched,
but it could happen.
Okay, here he comes.
Would you just help me?
Help me, please.
Let me linger by
your side Hi. Hi, Pop.
Can I talk to you
for one second?
I can't. Sun, moon and
tide wait for no man.
This will just take a second.
What's the matter with you?
You look like somebody died.
Um...
- Billy, why don't you sit down?
- I don't have time.
Going over to Anita's.
She's cooking up the fish
we caught this morning.
Sit down, Pop.
What the heck's going on?
Um...
Uh... Well, uh, Cliff...
Uh... We, um...
We're concerned about you.
Why? I feel great.
Well, actually, uh, we're
more concerned about Anita.
Nothing wrong with her either.
What you see, it's all her.
Hair, teeth.
I asked.
You didn't know her a week ago.
Now you're talking about
taking her to Europe.
What about all those expensive
gifts you've been buying her?
Buying stuff and going
places is what money's for.
What do you want me to do?
Hoard it like Mr. Skinflint over here?
Look, how about we say
that you just go
a little slower?
You know, get to know the real her.
Do things that don't cost any money.
Go for walks, canoe rides.
Think about what
might be going on here.
You're saying
Anita's a gold digger?
- No...
- Mind your own business, Clifford.
Ben?
Billy, don't get mad.
I get it. You started this.
I didn't start anything.
You're doing this
because you're jealous.
- I'm not jealous.
- I got something you don't.
I got a girl. You
ain't got a girl.
And that's what it is,
Benny Boy. You're jealous.
You want my girl? You
ain't gonna get my girl.
You know why?
Because I'm the cat's meow.
- Hey, Ben.
- Aah!
I wish you wouldn't do that.
- They're gonna hit the bank.
- What?
These prove it.
Took them yesterday morning.
When they were casing
the bank, I was casing them.
- Don't prove anything.
- Oh, no?
That is the security box
that he's checking out.
And Thomas Crighton told the
motel that he'd be leaving tomorrow,
and Lamont has to have his
boat out of the marina by noon.
That still doesn't prove
anything. What are you doing?
I'm sketching a rough
blueprint of the bank.
I walked through as much
of it as I could yesterday,
committed it to my
photographic memory.
It's crude, but it
should enable me
to, uh, figure out where
to position everyone.
What do mean?
I mean that it is time
for you to call the police.
I'm not calling the police.
The money is due to arrive at the
bank at 10:30 tomorrow morning.
Now, I believe that
they will make their move
while they're transferring
it into the vault.
You believe. That's no proof.
Ben, the proof
is in the pudding.
The proof is...
What the hell does that mean?
It means that I'm
not wrong about this,
and you must call the police.
On one condition.
Give me your word that you'll
be nowhere near that bank
when this thing goes down.
You're not serious.
I got to have your word.
All right. All right.
You have my word.
How many cops are there?
- Well, all the tellers. I guess 20.
- Oh.
There's the guy that
drives the getaway car.
Hi.
And here comes the money.
- Clear?
- Yeah, it's clear.
Let's do this.
Ah... Uh... See
that guy over there?
- Yeah.
- I mean, do you see him?
- Get him out of here.
- All right.
Hey, Charlie, how are you doing?
Just fine, thank you.
Hey, I've got some
cans for you over here.
Shh, shh, shh.
Okay.
You know, Ben's
really ticked off at you.
I couldn't help myself.
Well, no harm done.
Look, you probably wanna
stay here, so I'll see you later.
Oh, no, no, no. You're
going back to the motel.
And to make sure,
I'm going with you.
And don't try any of your
crazy schemes, all right?
No funny business. Come on.
No, no, no. Ed, no, no, no.
I just wanna see something.
I don't think this is a good idea. I
don't even know what you're doing.
Think about this.
Ron Jaffe walks into a bank
he doesn't have an account in.
He walks around,
and then he leaves.
What does that mean?
It means that we're about
to do something really stupid.
- Ben's gonna get really mad at me.
- Oh, Ben'll be fine.
He's not gonna be fine. You
don't care what Ben thinks.
- Anybody home?
- What are you doing?
- This is Dennis Lamont's boat.
- No.
- Maybe he's in the cabin.
- No. Why don't we...?
- Anybody home?
- Let's call and let's find out.
Ed, now this is wrong. Ed. Ed.
- Ed?
- Doesn't seem like there is.
You can't do this.
This is trespassing.
Trespassing is wrong. It's illegal.
They're gonna revoke your bail.
You know what that means?
You're gonna go to jail.
What are these?
Well... Aah, this is
no navigation chart.
They're supposed
to be blueprints
of Security Central Bank,
- but it's not.
- It's not?
No, they're fakes.
They're nothing like it.
Crighton must have dummied them up
knowing that if and when I found them,
I'd think that's where
they were gonna hit.
Yeah, the blueprints,
casing the bank the other day,
Jaffe today.
It was all a big decoy.
And I fell for it.
- Damn it!
- Ed, what are you doing?
Because of my stupidity,
they are probably out
pulling a heist right now.
I gotta find out where they are.
Ed.
That's it. That's it, listen to
me. Listen to me, I'm serious.
If you don't come with me
now, I'm gonna call the police.
Don't touch that phone.
Automatic redial.
Black and White Cab Company.
Come on, Melissa. Come
on, come on, come on.
- That's it, me too.
- You got it.
How are you gonna
find him in here?
By looking.
Hey.
- Hey, watch it, man.
- Excuse me.
What?
Back off, jerk!
FBI. Shut your face.
I'm with him.
Bingo.
Ron Jaffe's car.
- It's not there.
- Let me see.
See? See? The
money's not there, man.
What the hell is going on?
Don't move. Just stay
right where you are.
Well, it took four years,
but I finally get to say
my three favorite words:
You're under arrest.
Are you joking? You
can't set them free.
What do you suppose
I charge them with?
Standing in a room?
Armed robbery.
They were trying to recover $7
million they stole four years ago.
There wasn't any
money in that motel room.
Well, there was.
- Question them.
- You know what I charged them with?
I charged them with
malicious vandalism.
And when they pay their
fine, they are free to go.
And you're lucky I
don't throw you in jail,
along with you.
- Now, wait a minute.
- For that fiasco back at the bank.
You tied up 20 of my
officers for four hours.
And what do I
have to show for it?
Don't you understand?
It was all a diversion.
Well, looky here,
boys, it's Ed Wingate.
I say we sue him
for false arrest.
I assume you're aware that this
mentally challenged individual
is out on bail
and therefore prohibited
from carrying a gun?
It wasn't a gun. It was a toy.
Well, a fake gun
for a fake FBI agent.
Seems kind of
fitting, doesn't it?
Where's the 7
million bucks, boys?
You still singing that
same old song, Ed?
This isn't over.
Well, it better be,
because you harass
me one more time,
I'm gonna haul you into court,
and I'll hang your
pathetic butt out to dry.
Well, as your lawyer
I need to warn you,
he could do that.
But, Ben,
my butt is already bone-dry.
You tore up my floor
because you were drunk?
When I drink, I get
destructive. It's, uh...
It's a bad childhood thing.
Yes, ma'am, I've seen him
demolish entire kitchenettes. It's...
Well, needless to
say, I'm terribly sorry.
Will you put that
thing out, please?
Sorry.
Do you have any idea how
much the repairs are gonna cost?
About $1,200.
And I can't rent that unit out
for a week, so that'll cost me.
Well, I'll tell you what.
I'll give you $2,000
in cash, right now.
I mean, that ought to
cover it, don't you think?
If there's anything left
over, keep the difference.
Sure, okay.
Of course, I was hoping you'd
do me a little favor in return.
- What?
- Let me see your registration book.
It's against company policy,
so do it quick, okay?
There it is. I knew it.
Thank you.
They came in about a half
hour after you called me.
They were real interested
in this name right here.
"Al Ducow."
Checked in last
March, stayed one night.
- Who's Al Ducow?
- This proves I'm right, lieutenant.
They pulled the heist
off four years ago.
They buried the money
in that motel room.
The idea was they
wait a couple of years
till the heat is off
and then divvy it up.
Only it looks like this, uh, Al
Ducow came back ahead of schedule
so he could keep all
the money for himself.
But now he's dead.
When did that happen?
Three days ago.
He dropped dead at
the end of the triathlon.
Finished right next
to Thomas Crighton.
Well, you're awful
quiet over there.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
Kind of blue, I guess.
Poor baby.
You know I told you I was
gonna take you to Lake Como?
Yeah.
Well, it turns out I can't.
Got a business
trip I forgot about.
Of course, I could
take you with me.
Where are you going?
Terre Haute.
Indiana.
Wanna come?
- Well...
- Anita.
Ralph. Aah!
Good to see you.
How are you? I thought
you moved to Florida.
That I did.
And then I found I missed the
sound of your lovely, lilting voice,
and I turned around,
and homeward bound.
And now, seeing
you again, rejoice.
Oh, Ralph, you are so
talented and so sweet.
Ralph Fowler,
this is Billy Lewis.
Ralph's an old friend.
Billy's a new friend.
- Hello, Billy.
- Hello.
What's all that rejoice stuff?
Ralph writes poems
for greeting cards.
Really?
Well, I'd love to stay
and talk to you two,
but this is the day I
have a project due.
- I'll call you later.
- Okay.
Nice meeting you, um...
- Billy.
Glad you're back.
Isn't he amazing?
He didn't remember my name.
He just forgot.
Poets are so scatterbrained.
I wrote a poem once.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Can't remember it.
You are so cute.
- Cuter than Ralph?
- Oh, stop that.
- Get the lines.
- What do you think he did
- with the money?
- Who knows.
But if there's anything left,
we'll never find it. That's for sure.
Oh, man.
I'm afraid you're not going
anywhere, Mr. Crighton.
I'm placing you under arrest
for the murder of Albert Ducow.
What? What the hell is
wrong with you people?
He died of a heart attack.
- The coroner did some more tests.
- At my suggestion.
And discovered that
heart attack was induced
by a chemical called Monocaine.
Almost impossible to spot
unless you're looking for it.
I'll handle this, Mr. Wingate.
He had to have ingested it
within a half hour of his death.
And since you were
the only one with him,
and since it's highly doubtful
that he poisoned himself...
Why would I kill him?
He was my friend.
So your buddies
wouldn't find out
that it was you that dug
up the money from the heist.
I'll handle this, Mr. Wingate.
Al Ducow was in Hawaii
when he supposedly
registered in that motel.
- Credit card records prove it.
- Mr. Wingate...
You registered at the
motel using his name.
You stole the money
and then you killed him
so these two would never
suspect it was really you
and not Al Ducow who
double-crossed them.
Mr. Wingate, shut up.
You can ask the questions
you want downtown.
Cuff him, book him. Let's go.
Ed,
I really want you to
remember this moment,
because you're gonna
regret it for the rest of your life.
Hey, hey, lieutenant.
Wait.
Maybe these other two fellas
ought to come downtown too.
All right, here he comes. Watch.
See that? He dropped
something in the cup.
Wanna see it again?
Where did you get this?
I saw a guy taping the race.
I tracked him down, and he
gave me a copy of his tape.
When the jury sees this,
your friend Mr. Crighton's
as good as convicted.
Yeah, I suspect when he sees
this, he'll wanna make a deal.
Yeah. If he was my
client, that's what I'd advise.
Well, what kind of deal?
The kind that'll put you in jail for
a minimum of three to five years.
Wait, you got nothing
to threaten me with.
You don't care if
Mr. Crighton tells the police
about that Charleston
armored car robbery?
Come on, you know
him better than we do.
What do you think he'll do?
Be a stand-up kind of guy
and not say anything
about you and Mr. Lamont?
Or sell you down the
river to save his own neck?
- What's your point?
- The point is
is I'm giving you a
chance to make a deal.
You tell us everything we
wanna know right here, right now,
and you agree to testify in court
when and if it becomes necessary,
and I'll get you immunity
from prosecution
for that armored car robbery.
Of course, now, if you refuse,
I'll just go on out and get Mr. Lamont
and give him a crack at the deal.
So, what do you say?
You throw in a cigarette,
you got yourself a deal.
Yeah, well, I'm
telling you it's a lie.
Are you saying that
you did not mastermind
that $7 million
armored car heist?
Of course not.
Well, Ron Jaffe just testified
under oath that you did.
Well, Ron Jaffe's lying.
Was he lying when he said
that you knew Kathy Bridges?
No, I knew her.
Well, when he said
that you brought her
aboard Mr. Lamont's
boat, was that a lie?
No, I brought her aboard.
Ah. When he said that she was
an old friend of yours, was that a lie?
Yes. I'd just met her.
Oh, when he said
that you were paying her to keep
tabs on my client, Ed Wingate,
was that a lie?
That is a lie.
When he said that Ed Wingate
had been hounding you and him
and the other two for years,
trying to pin this armored
car heist on them, truth or lie?
That's true.
Now, when he said that you
were not in your motel room
at the time of the
murder, truth or lie?
I'd just gone out for a run.
Oh, run, my eye.
You'd met up with
Kathy Bridges, killed her,
dumped her in Ed
Wingate's motel room
so the police would
find her there, blame him,
get him off your back
so you could go
ahead with your scheme
to keep all $7 million in stolen
money yourself, didn't you?
- Ahem.
- What?
Um, excuse me, Your Honor.
Um... Uh, um...
The defense has
no further questions.
This court is recessed until
10:00 tomorrow morning.
Police just busted a dealer
who said that Thomas
Crighton was with him
at the time of the murder.
He was buying the Monocaine
he used to kill Al Ducow.
So...
he committed that murder, but,
unfortunately for us, not this one.
Where were you when you saw him?
Oh, I was right out there
fixing the ice machine.
Yeah. You say you
heard footsteps over there?
Yeah, I heard somebody
fooling around with a lock.
Like he was having trouble
with his key or something.
And I looked over and I saw that
Wingate guy outside the room here.
Had a lady hanging all over
him like she was just totally blotto.
I called over to see if he wanted
some help. He didn't answer.
About a second later,
he got the door open,
kind of pulled that lady
into the room with him,
shut the door.
That's the last I saw
him till the police came.
- And you didn't see anybody leave?
- No.
And you were working on the
ice machine the whole time?
Yeah. Well, maybe not the
whole time, but most of the time.
And you're sure it
was Ed Wingate?
- Well, it was his room, wasn't it?
- Huh.
Where's that door go?
Oh, the room next door.
That door's always locked.
- You got a key?
- Oh, sure.
Hey, room in here's been
out of commission for a while.
Some pipes broke in
the bathroom upstairs.
Made a real mess.
No electricity. Nothing.
I was supposed to redo the
ceiling and redo the wallpaper.
Hadn't got around to
it before the murder,
and then since then,
everything around here just
come to a screeching halt.
Now, I don't know
when I'm gonna finish.
Don't. Don't go in there.
I had met Miss Bridges, yes.
Thomas brought her by
the boat one night for a drink.
Is that when he told you
that he had hired her to
keep tabs on Ed Wingate?
No, I don't recall
him saying that. No.
But you did know who Ed
Wingate was, didn't you?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, he'd
been hounding us for years,
trying to pin some
armored car robbery on us.
As it turns out,
he had good reason
to hound you, didn't he?
Because Mr. Jaffe testified
right here under oath
that you, he and the other two
did in fact pull off that robbery.
I can't comment on
that. Lawyer's orders.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
So what Mr. Jaffe told us
about how the four of you
came down here to Wilmington,
not to be in some triathlon,
but to dig up and
divide that stolen money,
I guess you can't
talk about that.
No, afraid not.
Yeah.
You know, it costs a lot of
money to own a big boat like yours.
You got mooring charges,
upkeep, fuel, utilities, taxes.
Not to mention the
original investment.
You rich, Mr. Lamont?
- Not really.
- No. Ha, ha.
No ways near it.
Truth is, you're in debt up
to your eyeballs, aren't you?
Well, isn't every
red-blooded American?
Yeah, yeah. Well, I suppose.
But you needed your share
of that stolen money bad.
And when you learned that
Ed Wingate was down here
spying on you fellas,
threatening to gum up the works,
you knew you had to
do something, didn't you?
None of what you're
saying is the least bit true.
Oh, yes, it is.
Yeah, it's all true.
And sad for you, I can prove it.
Have you ever been in the motel
where Ed Wingate was staying
when Kathy Bridges was killed?
The Seaview Motel?
- Never.
- Never been in his room
or any of the other rooms?
No, never.
Oh, uh...
What kind of shoes do you wear
when you're on that big boat of yours?
I wear deck shoes always.
Uh...
Deck shoes like these?
Yes.
If they look familiar,
they're yours.
I had the police get a warrant
and remove them from
your boat this morning.
Why would you
do a thing like that?
Well, because in the
room adjacent to Ed's room,
at the Seaview,
they found several
real nice footprints.
You see, there's nobody in
that room. It's unoccupied.
They're gonna redecorate
it. There's no electricity.
There's no rug on the floor,
and there's dust everywhere.
So let me show you.
Let me show you.
They found these
shoe prints, see?
Isn't that nice?
And when they compared
and analyzed these shoe prints,
they determined that they were
made by a pair of deck shoes like these.
So what? Half the people in
Wilmington have shoes just like mine.
Yeah, that's right.
But they don't walk like you do.
See, when you walk,
you what they call pronate.
You turn your
ankles in like that.
And that means
that you wear the inside
of the heels of your shoes
more than the outside.
You see there?
And when you figure your weight,
how old the shoes are, the size,
well, the shoe print is, uh, just
about as unique as a fingerprint.
So when they compared
this shoe print here
with these shoes, guess what.
Perfect match.
Now, how could you
have left shoe prints
in a room you were never in?
Well, that's easy.
The police made a mistake.
Wouldn't be the first
time, now, would it?
No.
But you know how these
prints got there, so do I.
And the police.
You met up with
Kathy Bridges that night,
and somewhere along the
line, probably in your car,
you put on a pair of gloves and
you strangled the life out of her.
And drove over to Ed Wingate's
motel, picked the lock to his room,
dumped her body there.
Then you stole the briefcase
that had those pictures of all of you
that she was telling you about.
The problem was somebody
saw you go in that room,
so you couldn't go back.
So what you did,
you picked the lock
to the room next door.
You couldn't turn the lights on,
and you had no way of knowing
there was dust everywhere.
And you were leaving
behind proof positive
that you're the killer.
The bad part is your
friend Thomas Crighton,
because of him,
your share of that $7
million was long gone.
So you killed Kathy Bridges
and framed Ed Wingate
for nothing, didn't you?
Hey, Jer.
- Hey, Cliff.
- Agh!
Hey, Ed, what are you doing?
The party's in your honor.
You're not supposed to be cooking.
Oh, you want something
done right, do it yourself.
Nothing I hate worse than
an ill-prepared hamburger.
Those burgers
actually smell good.
Here.
Why, thank you.
Try not to burn mine, okay?
- So you went for a run?
- Yeah, yeah, a short one.
You know, Cliff, I'm really
impressed with what you did.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I thought it was great.
So, what does that mean?
She was really
impressed with what I did.
Does that mean she likes me?
She wants me to ask her
out? What does that mean?
Slow and steady wins the race.
I thought it was the
race is to the swift.
Hmm.
Good point.
I'll get it.
Now, either play something romantic
or cut it out, would you please?
Anita's here.
Hi, come on in. We're
just getting ready to eat.
No, I, um...
I'm not gonna stay.
Thanks, anyway.
Something wrong?
Well, I've been seeing Ralph.
You know the fellow you met
on the beach the other day?
The guy who talks in rhymes?
We've always had
this connection, and...
Well, seeing him again,
I realized that the fire
between us is still burning.
So, um, I'm returning
the necklace,
and I won't be seeing
you again, Billy.
You're dumping me?
Well, call me superficial.
It's just that Ralph is special.
He's a starving artist, I
know, but he is an artist.
And I just find that,
heh, irresistibly romantic.
Artist? He writes
greeting cards.
I'm sorry.
Bye-bye, Billy.
Here we go.
Now, be careful, this is hot.
Come and get it.
Hey, Pop, dinner's ready.
Poppie, your favorite.
She dumped me.
For a guy who dresses like
a bum and writes bad poetry.
Well, 'tis better to have loved and
lost than never to have loved at all.
Look who the wind blew in.
We're sorry, Billy.
Well, you ought to be.
All of you made me think
she was after my money,
and she wasn't.
Well, Billy, it's just one of
those things that didn't work out.
There'll be others.
Others?
That woman put a spring in my
step and made my heart skip a beat.
Hey, Pop, that
was just like poetry.
Yeah. That was like poetry.
Wonder if it's too
late to call her again.
Yeah, it's too late.
Well, Billy, we are all sorry.
Well, if you're ready for love,
it'll find you.
Know what that means, Ben?
Means I'm ready and you're not.
You better shape up.
www.tvsubtitles.net